Guide to the Irving Godt Papers 1952-2002 (Bulk 1970-1992) MC 206
New York University Archives
Irving Godt Papers
Bulk, 1970-1992
1952-2002
MC 206
New York University Archives
39.5 linear feet (37 boxes)
The Papers of Irving Godt comprise the pedagogical and research works of a music professor who taught at both universities and liberal arts colleges during his career. Included are his correspondence with colleagues and publishers, lecture notes and lesson plans, and original works of music and fiction.
Godt, Irving
Provenance
Dr. Godt's daughter donated the collection to New York University in 2007. Additional research materials relating to Marianna Martines were received in 2010.
Access Restrictions
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
The first 35 boxes of this collection are in
off-site storage
, and you must contact the repository for access.
Biography
Irving Godt received his Ph.D. in historical musicology from New York University's Graduate School of Arts and Sciences in 1969. His dissertation, titled Guillaume Costeley (1531-1606): Life and Works, focused on his interest in early Renaissance music. While at NYU he studied under Jan LaRue and Gustave Reese. Prior to 1970 he taught courses at the University of Minnesota, Claremont College, and the Univerity of Illinois at Urbana. In 1970 he accepted a teaching position at Indiana University of Pennsylvania (IUP), where he taught until 2003. While his specialty remained Renaissance music, he taught every undergraduate and graduate course in music at IUP throughout his career there.
Godt was a founding member of the Allegheny Chapter of the American Musicological Society and has published more than 60 articles in scholarly musicological journals on a variety of topics. On December 5, 2006 he passed away at his home in Indiana, Pennsylvania.
Sources:
Rakhonen, Carl. "In memoriam: Irving Godt, 1923-2006." Allegheny Chapter of the American Musicological Society, Recent Chapter News. Found online at: http://www.people.iup.edu/rahkonen/AllegAMS/recentnews.htm.
Scope and Content
The bulk of materials contained in this collection include handwritten notes and musical scores from Godt's time as a student at Brooklyn College and NYU; various typed drafts of Godt's professional writings and articles; course-related materials from his time at IUP including syllabi, supplementary materials and lectures; drafts for his Musica Polyglossa (a computer assisted thesaurus of musical terms); correspondence with journal editors and publishers; and personal writings, mainly poems and short stories about topics other than music.
Series VII of this collection is an accretion that consists of his research on 18th-century composer Marianna Martines. The bulk of materials contained in this series include reproductions of Martines musical scores; reproductions of letters and writings from Martines; drafts of journal articles and books on the composer; and correspondence with publishers, advisors, colleagues and archivists.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged roughly by series.
The files are grouped into seven series:
Student materials
Teaching materials
Correspondence
Publications
Unpublished writings
Miscellaneous material, including unpublished poetry
Marianna Martines research material
American Musicological Society.; Godt, Irving; Indiana University of Pennsylvania.; IUP Chorale.; LaRue, Jan, 1918-2004; Martinez, Marianne, 1744-1812; New York University. Graduate School of Arts and Science.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents).; Lecture notes.; Lectures.; Music |y 18th century.; Music |y 19th century.; Poems.; Scores.; Short stories.; Syllabi.
- Series I: Student Materials
  - Guillaume Costeley: His Life and Works, Vol. I (doctoral thesis by Irving Godt), undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Guillaume Costeley: His Life and Works, Vol. I, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Guillaume Costeley: His Life and Works, Vol. II, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guillaume Costeley: His Life and Works, Vol. II, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Guillaume Costeley: His Life and Works, Vol. II, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Binder containing paper by Godt titled "A Descriptive Tool for Paraphrase and a Josquin Application," as well as published articles and class notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ARCADELT, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Counterpoint, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous student materials, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Symphony course (LaRue), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Intro to Musicology, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Aetniop: A Play With Various Musical Versions", undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn College--Miscellaneous Materials, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Seminar in Style Criticism, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Final exams, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Three binders of printed musical scores, various (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Wagner, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Reese: Late Renaissance Final Exam & Cram Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - One binder of handwritten scores, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Baroque Seminar: LaRue, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Beethoven-Schubert, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Baroque, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - History, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Reese's Advanced Seminar: Class Notes, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gretry: Richard Coeur De Lion, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - School Music: Degrees in Music, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "On Melodic Unity in Gretry's Richard Coeur de lion", 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - LaRue's Baroque and Classical Performance Practice: Class Notes, Assignments, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hi-Fi, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Aethiop: A Play with Various Musical Versions in England and America, 1812-1869, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - LaRue's Symphony Before Beethoven: Printed lists, short papers, and final exam (prepared) notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Book "Review": Lowinsky, Tonality and Atonality in 16th-century Music (seminar paper), undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Report: The Beneventan Gradual, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - LaRue's Wellesley Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Teares…(1614): Term Paper in Professor Reese's Introduction to Musicology, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sir William Leighton's The Teares or Lamentacions of a Sorrowfvll Sovle (1614), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Aspects of Dealers' Catalogs, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Instrumental Music of the Romantic Period: Class notes, papers, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Orpheus Chamber Singers: Hunter College, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - NY ProMusica Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mus 508, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Monteverdi's Arianna: A Study of Various Aspects of the Fragment": Part I, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - L'Estocart Psalter, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Course outline, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Early Operas--Compilation, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Holy Manna, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous handwritten copied scores, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Extracurricular lecture notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Johan Joachim Agrell: Seven Symphonies: Transcriptions by members of LaRue's class in The Symphony Before Beethoven, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NYU, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Brooklyn, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Prof. Leighton--Teares of Lamentations, copy with facsimiles, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Music History Seminar, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Seminar in Style Criticism, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Baroque Seminar Class Projects (Outlines, bibliographies. Etc.), undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Brooklyn, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Rhythmic Modes, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Mus 131, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Series II: Teaching Materials
  - Guillaume DuFay, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Morton, Robert: L'Omme Arme, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mozart: String Quartet #14 in G, K. 387, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Marriage of Figaro--synopsis, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 18-c Mus. World (Mozart), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mus Def, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mussorgsky: Boris Godunov, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mussorgsky: Boris Godunov (Translation), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Maria Zart Obrecht, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ockeghem, Binchois, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ockeghem: Missa Proclationem: Kyrie, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Peter Phillips: LXXII: Amarilli di Julio Romano, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Purcell: Ah! Belinda! From Dido and Aeneas, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Purcell: Recitative (#7) Dido and Aeneas, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mus 301, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Music Examples (scores), undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Intro to Graduate Studies in Music, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Collegium Musicum: Pronunciation Guide, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Music 51--Class, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Mus 51--Grout on chart, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Exam #2--Mus 51, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Exam #3--Mus 51, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Exam #5--Mus 51, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Final Exam--51, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Mus 52--Exam 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Mus 52--Exam 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Quiz #3 and 4--Mus 52, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Music 53--Study Questions, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Mus 51 & 2--Class Notes--University of Minnesota, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Verdi, Rigoletto--Synopsis, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - A5 Mus 301--Translations, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Bach: Suite in B Minor, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Music History 302, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - A11 Listening Assignment, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Listening Assignment, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Pittsburgh Madrigal Singers, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Pittsburgh Madrigal Singers, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Western Pennsylvania Symposium on World Literature, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - IUP Music Department materials, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Baroque Festival, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - A Reading of the Eroica--Beethoven, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Mus 301--Supplementary Study Materials, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Marcello Hand-out Masters, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Humanities II, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Mozart; K 52, course materials, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Plain Chant, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Secular Monophony, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Medieval Polyphony I, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - 16th C, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Baroque, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Late 16th-Century-early 17th Century (Baroque), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - 15th C, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - 14th C, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Notation: Display copies, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous course materials (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous course materials (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Clasroom examples--Monophony, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Course evaluations, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Musical Language of the 18th Century, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Work & Concert Pack, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Most Momentous Development, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Josquin Desprez--Thematic Coherence, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Classroom examples, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Ref: Trent, Lasso, Palestrina, Byrd, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1600: Early Opera, Monteverdi, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Organum to Duustable, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Burgundy to Josq, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Monophony, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Enlightenment: Mannheim to C.P.E. Bach, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Classroom examples: Tape contents, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Early History of Music Writing in the West, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Beethoven & Romantic--SHMRG, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Couperin, Romani, Covelli, Tovelli, Vivaldi, Bach, Handel, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Schutz-Purcell, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Frottola-Madrigal Chanson, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Old Musical Instruments, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Handel, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Handel, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Josquin, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Costeley (Godt), undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Costeley (Godt), undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Costeley (Godt), undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bartok (Works), undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Music History I (Music Assignments), undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - MUS 303--Music History III, Supplementary Study Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Costeley Scores, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Medieval and Renaissance Listening Tapes--Contents, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - MUS 303--Music History III, Supplementary Study Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Style Analysis and Schenkerian Analysis, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Generalized Style Analysis, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - History of Choral Music, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Tesei, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ecuadorian Ethnomusicology: A Preliminary Introduction Into Ecuador's Mesomusica (not Godt's course), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - MH 302: Music History II (Indiana University of Pennsylvania), undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - MUS 302, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Humanities: Lecture #1 and Exhibit #1 (Plainchant), undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Mus. 130 Intro., undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies from *Polyphonic Music of the Fourteenth Century*, ed. Leo Schrade: Vol. I, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 20th-Century Style Elements, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 12: Schubert, Schumann, Mendelssohn, Berlioz, Chopin, Liszt, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Marcello: Missa Clementius, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Indiana University of Pennsylvania Department of Music: Notes and Scraps for Music 508, Music of the Sixteenth Century (and American Music), undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - RT I, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - RT II, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Classroom Examples: Music 101, Musical Form & Forms, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Teaching Materials (from binder), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Possente Spirito, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Collegium Musicum: Pronunciation Guide, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Music Examples, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Nolo Mortem Peccatoris, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Grocheo: Motet defined, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Handel Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hawk Burn, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Franz Josef Haydn--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Haydn--Symphony #104 in D, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Joseph Haydn: The Creation (Erster Teil) Parts 1-4, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Haydn--Symphony #104 (#1), undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Haydn--Symphony #104, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hindemith--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hindemith Craft, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Hindemith Works (Pg. 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Hindemith--Craft of Composition, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Hindemith--Mathes der Mahler (Part 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Liszt--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Ludwig van Beethoven--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Jean-Baptiste Lully--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Luther on Music, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Machaut--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Marenzio--Zefiro torna, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Mendelssohn: Octet, op. 20, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - A 20 (3): Mendelssohn Octet, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Monteverdi: Orfeo, Prologo (Analysis) A, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Monteverdi: Orfeo, Prologo (Analysis) B, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Monteverdi: Orfeo, Prologo (Analysis) bass lines, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Monteverdi: Orfeo, Possente Spirito, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Monteverdi: Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Monteverdi: Ohime dov e il mio ben, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Monteverdi: Lamento della Niufa, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Monteverdi: Ecco mormorar l'onde, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Monteverdi: Ecco mormorar, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Hindemith: Mathis der Maler 1, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Josquin Desprez, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Josquin--Missa de BV, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Josquin: M. Pangolingua Gloria, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Jacapo & Landini--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - J.S. Bach--Family, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - J.S. Bach--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Landini--Gran Piani, undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Landini--Gran Piani agli'ochi music, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Lasso: Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous music scores, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous teaching materials, undated (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous teaching materials, undated (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Madrigalisms in the Credo de Rege, undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Gilbert + Sullivan--Course Materials, undated (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - R. Strauss--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Strauss, Richard--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Stravinsky--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Thematic Transf., undated (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Bedrich Smetana--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Stamic, undated (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Heinrich Schutz 1585-1672 Kostritz-Dresden, undated (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Tchaikovsky--Sym. 6 Durch = brochene Arbeit, undated (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Schumann--1840, undated (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Schumann--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Schumann--Carnaval, undated (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - R.A. Schumann: Dichterliebe (a song cycle on texts by H. Heine), undated (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Schubert: Phantasie CP. 15, undated (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Schubert: An die Musik, undated (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Schub + Schum Song, undated (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Schubert--The Wanderer (Der Wanderer), undated (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Schubert: Wanderer Fantasy--Analysis, undated (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - My Sweet Repose P. 1: Schubert, undated (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - My Sweet Repose P. 2: Schubert, undated (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - My Sweet Repose P. 3: Schubert, undated (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - My Sweet Repose P. 4: Schubert, undated (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Schoenberg--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Rossini--Barber of S., undated (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Romanticism, undated (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Defining Romanticism, undated (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Ramean Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Purcell--Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - H. Purcell--Overture to Dido and Aeneas, undated (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Music 52--Listening Folder, undated (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - History of Theory, undated (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Mus. 420--Sem. In Mus. Lit., undated (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Tape 12, undated (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Mus 52--2nd Year, undated (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Intro. To Musicology, undated (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Hist. of Kbd. Mus., undated (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Music of Cervantes Tape 10, undated (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Affektenlehre, undated (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Lect. 8, undated (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Lecture #10 Baroque II ("Middle"), undated (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Humanities II: Listening Assign. 7a, undated (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Humanities II: Listening Assignment 7b, undated (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Lecture 6, undated (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Lect. 7, undated (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Humanities II: Tape I, undated (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Lecture 9, undated (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Reese Symposium 1974 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Hum. II, Tape 11, undated (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Dragoni: "Zefiro torma", undated (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Ad hoc Committee GFU '69, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - 16th Century Modes & Solmization, undated (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Brahms, Opera, Wagner, Verdi, undated (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Zefiro, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Studying for Exams, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Style Periods of Music History, Appendix A, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Syllabus 301/2 Masters, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Translations: Music 301, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Classicism, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Petrarcha, Petrarchism, and Music, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Theory and Practice of Sixteenth-Century Music, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Zarlino: On the Modes, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Series III: Research Materials
  - Miscellaneous Research Materials, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Music Scores (copies), undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Anthology of "Madrigal, etc.", undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bach--misc. materials, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Research--Glass Armonica, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Bohemia--copy, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Research Materials--French, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Fucci--Photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "Mozart's Real Joke"--Research Materials, various (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Arianna, various (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Unlabeled, various (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Schering, Arnold--Misc. Research, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Shering, Arnold--Misc. Research, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Kirkpatrick, Ralph--Misc. Research, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Schering, Arnold--Misc. Research, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Canons, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Absalom Materials--Folder 2, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Absalom Materials--Folder 3, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Absalom Materials--Folder 4, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Absalom Materials--Folder 5, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - A Major Angel Concert in Ferrara--Research Materials, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Ferrara Photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Absalom Materials--Folder 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - List of Bibliographies, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Misc. Programs/Scores, various (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Benedetto Marcello, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Zefiro torna, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Two motets, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - The Mass of Barcelona, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Catalogue of Musical Subjects (Fresco-Style), undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - WP Readings of Selected Comps., undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Fucci 1, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Various photocopied works (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Fiala, etc. Monteverdi Lamento d'Arianna, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Research Memorandum, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Old Hall Manuscript--Mass Music, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Josquin: Ave mundi 2, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Benedetto Marcello Score--Messa a 4 voci, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Arianna, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Josq. Ave mundi, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)